Juan Carlos Calix

SKILLS

I am a C# developer so I was studying a Bachelor of Science in Information Technology and I have been 3 years of experience as a C# Developer. So I have over 10-year experience in IT and I was working also As a Support Services, Field Tech, Server Administrator, Network Administrator.

EXPERIENCE

Unified Communication Group, Everett WA.—Tech Fiber

OCT 2020 - PRESENT

Responsibilities:

- Install and maintain inside wire for residential/business broadband (HSI/Video) service.
- Install Central Office and B-box junctions as required for broadband continuity, digital subscriber carriers and associated broadband equipment, such as DSLAMS (Digital subscriber line access multiplexer), Residential Gateways and HSI (High-Speed Interface) business class routers.
- Install an array of wireless home networking equipment. Other equipment will include FTTH (Fiber to the House).
- Communicate effectively and accurately on customer issues to eliminate repeat trouble calls.
- - Support, install and repair company products and services.

Caracol Knits, Potrerillos, Cortes Honduras — Analyst Programmer System (Software Engineer)

Sept 2013 - Dic 2016

Responsibilities:

- Built, tested, and deployed scalable, highly available, and modular software products.
- Collaborated with other developers to identify and alleviate the number of bugs in the software.
- Collaborated with product management to design, build and test systems.
- Developed and implemented Query's using SQL Server.
- Debugged and modified software components.
- Coding in C#
- Test Driven Development.
- Work Agile Scrum.
- MVVM.
- TSF
- Dependency Injection
- LinQ to SQL
- Silverlight in the Front End.

Extralum , San Pedro Sula, Cortes Honduras — Support Service and Server Administrator

Sept 2006 - August 2013

Responsibilities:

- Completed inventory counts and organized supplies.
- Updated documentation and produce reports.
- Applied troubleshooting and diagnostic skills to resolve a range of issues.
- Monitored network performance and provided network performance statistical reports for both real-time and historical measurements.
- Responded to telephone, email and in person inquiries regarding [Item] operation, use and repair.
- Advocated for end-users to perform testing and problem analysis for server, desktop and IT infrastructure work.
- Managed creative projects from concept to completion while managing outside vendors.
- Recommended network security standards to management.
- Collaborated with clients from concept through final delivery of product or service.
- Administrator server 2013
- ISA server 2006 less

EDUCATION

Edmonds Community College , Lynnwood WA, — General Education Development

- A GED® is accepted as an equivalent to a high school diploma by most employers in Washington state and many other states.
- A GED® is accepted by most college admissions officers.
- Students who take courses to help become ready for the GED receive individual academic advising, access to college courses in English and math, and transitional support towards college level classes at Edmonds College.
- Earning a GED® demonstrates a level of learning that meets or exceeds the performance of the top two-thirds of U.S high school graduates.

Universidad Nacional Autonoma del Valle de Sula(UNAH-VS) , San Pedro Sula, Honduras — Information Technology

41 classes were approved of 52.

Oriented system and Network System and programming.

Skill

- .NET Development.
- SQL Server,
- ReactJS.,
- Network Administration.
- Support Service,
- Customer service,
- NodeJS(BackEnd)

My Github My Linkedin